Thank you for watching!
Hello everyone!
Yes! I'm Blue Rilla and White Giri!
Nice to meet you!
Yay! Yay!
The battle is coming!
What prefecture and what city are we in now?
We will be there!
Well then, Lilah, give us a hint!
Yes, I'll give you a hint!
Well, thank you very much.
Lilah, I'll say it just once. I'm sorry.
Sorry.
That's how you use it.
You want to use it?
I'm practicing.
LOL!
Laughing.
Yes, sorry, excuse me.
I'll go once, sorry.
LOL!
Please! Please!
Yes, please!
Okay, I'll go now.Well, I'll be going!
Yes, sir!
I'm going around the village.
Two outs in three seconds.
Three seconds.
Two seconds.
3 seconds ago
Hello everyone!
Yes! I'm Liloa Aoi and Miyu Yanagi!
Nice to meet you!
Yay!
Yes! So, here we are!
Here is a quiz!
What prefecture and what city are we in?
Then, Liloa, please take the quiz!
I'll give you a hint.
Quiz...
Oh, I made a mistake.
Yes! Suddenly, we have a quiz!
This is Mr. Leroy.
What prefecture and what city are we in?
Well, Leroy, give us a hint.
Here we go.
Did you get it?
One more time.
Keep your voice down.
Stop.
You understand?You understand.
I understand now.
I'm sure.
Lila, the correct answer is...
Stop.
We're in Stop City, Fukuoka.
Can I repeat the explanation?
What's the explanation?
It's Ya-Mei-Cha.
And 8.
What's eight?
What's this?
Does it mean "stop"?
Yes, that's what it means.
Yes, that's what I mean.
Why did you come to Quit Market?
Earlier, you proposed the idea of making picture books out of recycled plastic bottles.
We came up with the idea.
The executive committee members of Murakata-san discussed the idea and decided to proceed with the project.
There is a place in Quit City that can make paper.
Yes.
I came to Yume City this time to ask about making picture books.
I'm here to discuss with you about making picture books.
Yay!
Picture book making?
He's going to make a picture book.
It's amazing, isn't it?
It's going to be a picture book made out of paper.
So, today's goal is...
To learn how to make paper from plastic bottles.The method of making paper from plastic bottles is to learn and
To request your help in making a picture book.
Good luck!
Let's go.
Okay, goodbye.
You're nervous, right? Yes, I am.
Why are you nervous?
It's our first time on location.
Usually, one of the older members supports us.
But it's just the two of us.
Actually, actually...
It may look like this, but it's our first time.
I don't know if you can see it.
I'm a little nervous. Actually, I am.
Shall we go?
Let's go!
I don't think I'm going to make it.
You've got your parasol.
Hey...
But you know, it's cooler than in the daytime.
It's cooler. I'm glad. It's cooler. There's a breeze.
It's kind of...
It's green.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's beautiful.
I knew it.
Cha-cha-cha! So...
I want to drink it.
I want a drink.
Do you have one? Near here.
Yamaichan farm. Ya-ya-ya field.
Looks like it.
Let's pile it up a little bit.
But you know what? At the end...
Onions.
Then it smelled like onions.
I could smell it.
It smells like tea.
It's tea.
This could be great.
Oh, I see it.
Oh!
Is this it?
Do we have to walk 100 meters?
I don't know where the entrance is.
I'm sure.
What is it?
What if it's not?
If I'm wrong, it's 8.2.
Excuse me.
It's so bright.
Hello.
I'm Sakaguchi from Nakamura Paper Mills.
We're the battening team.
We're Leroy Blue and Mie Yanagi.
Pleased to meet you.
What kind of company is Nakamura Paper Mills?
Our company was founded 150 years ago this year
150 years? That's amazing!
We're a company that makes machine-loving Japanese paperWe are a company that makes a kind of machine-loving Japanese paper.
We mainly make shoji paper.
but we also make various other types of paper.
I see.
We use a lot of it in our live performances.
We use it as a set ourselves.
We move things like this ourselves.
I see.
What we make is not just
It's not just shoji paper.
It's not just shoji paper, but also
UV cut
amazing
A little expensive paper
When you look through it in the light, the pattern comes out.
Stylish
Tear-resistant cut
Shoji paper with various functions
We make that kind of paper.
That's amazing!
I bought one on my own.
That's right.
I didn't know there were that many kinds.
That's amazing!
I'll let you two try it.
Try it out.
I wanted you to try our paper.
What a tiny little shoji!
It's true!
These are tiny shoji. This is a tiny shoji.
This looks like the same paper.
I think it looks like the same kind of shoji paper.
Yes, it does.
Then, let's take this paper.
Just for fun.
Try to tear it by pushing it with your finger.
Are you sure?
Yes, sir.
Ready?
Oh, it's too hard!
Oh, I can't tear it!
It's unbreakable.
Oh, wow.
Uh-oh.
It's ripped.
It ripped, didn't it?
Yes, sir
It's just an ordinary shoji paper
It feels like it's being pushed.
It's pretty heavy and strong.
Next, let's look at this shoji paper.
Just like before, press down with your finger
and try to tear it.
I'll tear it.
Ready?
Oh, it's so hard!
Oh, it's hard.
Uh, hard.Eh, hard
It's hard.
Wait, wait.
My finger hurts.
It hurts.
I can't tear this.
This one does.
It won't tear.
This is how we make tear-resistant shoji paper.
Wow!
I thought the first one was too hard.
Wow, it won't tear.
You can't play with it. You can't play with it.
That's for sure.
Little kids in kindergarten and such don't tear it too much even if you hit it hard.
Wow, that's amazing.
We make a lot of unique shoji paper like that.
That's interesting.
Here you go, Seiki's.
Oh, it's hard.
It's hard.
Why?
It hurts my fingers.
What? I don't know.
Is this kind of thing rare?
No, there are a lot of them.
Sometimes they're just made of paper.
Often, the surface is coated. It is common to have a coating on the surface
that are coated on the surface.
It's a little difficult for air to pass through.
Is it hot?
Yes, it's hot.
It allows air to pass through.
It's normal paper.
Shoji paper allows air to pass through to some extent.
So light can pass through it.
So it's hard to tear without changing that feature.
It's amazing!
It is a paper that is hard to tear.
Even though it's so hard, it allows air and light to pass through.
Wow!
Sounds comfortable.
We'd like to learn more about making paper for picture books.
Can we learn something here?
We actually make paper.
You can see how we make paper.
You can see how we make paper and learn a little more about it.
How about it?
Yes! I look forward to working with you.
Thank you very much.
I'll show you around.
Pleasure to meet you.
A tour to look forward to. A tour of the world, huh?
I don't know, Master.
This is where we make our paper.
We'll go right in.
Let's go in. Let's go in.
Oh, my God.
Here you go.
Thank you
Cool
Cool.
Do you smell my hair?
Maybe.
But what?
Which one?
What do you think it smells like?
I don't know if it's hair, but I might smell it.
What's that smell? This one.
What's that smell?
We're here every day.
But maybe the hair smell is right.
Oh, so this is what hair smells like.
Wow.
This is the actual factory space where they make the hair.
These curtains are meant to keep insects out.
That's why we put them up.
We don't want any complaints or complaints about bugs in the hair.
We don't like the way it looks, do we?
So they are doing their best to prevent insects from getting into the hair.
That's great.
Let's see here.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me for interrupting. Excuse me for disturbing you.
What's going on?
So much stuff. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, it's huge.
Wow.
There are stores that are inside stores that are inside stores.
It might not be easy to get inside like this.
It doesn't have to be cool.
Thank you.
Amazing!
Looks amazing
I'm sorry, it's a little noisy, so I'm going to have to speak a little louder
Yes, yes.
In a manner of speaking, this is the process of making raw materials for paper, starting from this side.
And now, you see the square pile in front of you, right?
That is wood.
Wood?
Pulp is made from wood.
And this is a sheet of pulp.
Let me show you.
This is a sheet of pulp.
It's the raw material for paper.
You can actually touch it.
It's kind of floppy.
It's hot.
Even if the heat is good
It's still a bit far from what you imagine your hair to look like.
Yes, it is.
So if it keeps going like this, it still won't be hairSo if we keep this up, it's still not going to be hair.
So we're going to make this into a little bit of hair.
Yes, sir.
What do you mean by "cameplage"?
For example, there's a tree standing right now.
A lot of fibers are gathered in that tree.
The fibers are loosened and pressed together to make this bulbletschuk.
Turtles are made of a collection of those fibers.
And now, to make this sheet of pulp into paper
First, we dissolve it into a sludge.
Oh, it melts?
Here it is.
Oh, wow!
Dissolving!
We're dissolving the pulp sheet I mentioned earlier in water.
Wow!
It looks like cotton like this!
Wow! It's sludge!
If you look closely, can you see the fibers?
Yes, it is!
Yes, they are fibers!
When you break them up like this, they become fibers like this!
Wow! Amazing!
First, the pulp sheet is melted like this.
Then, we go to the next process.
Yes!
Next, the pulp you just melted into a sludge
This is transferred into the tank here.
Now, what you see here is called synthetic fiber.What you see here now is called synthetic fiber.
Like synthetic fibers.
Mix it with these synthetic fibers and so on.
It's just pulp paper.
But if you add other chemical fibers and various chemicals
the paper will have various functions.
Oh, I see!
The fact that it didn't tear when I poked it with my finger earlier is the result of mixing it with various chemical fibers.
I see! Not only that, but it can be broken in many ways.
There are various types of synthetic fibers, so the combination of these fibers can produce various functions.
Do you mix the two together, or do you mix them with plastic bottles?
We don't mix PET bottles as they are.
For example, plastic bottles are made of a resin called polyester.
We sometimes mix polyester resin with fine fibers like this.
We sometimes mix them.
There was the paper that didn't tear when you pressed it with your finger, right?
That was paper made by mixing polyester fibers.
It's hard!
Why?
It hurts my fingers!
It won't tear.
I've heard a lot about polyester.
So
If we can recycle plastic bottles and turn them into fiber
I think we will be able to put them in paper
Maybe we can make picture books from this.
Then here we have just mixed the synthetic fibers and other materials
Now it's time to make it into paper.
Now it's time to make it into paper. (at the) last moment
Here you go.
Oh!
We're actually making paper in this process here.
I think it was sludge just now.
Now, take a peek here.
It's very smooth, isn't it?
If it's smooth, it means that there are a lot of fibers mixed in.
There are no clumps, and it is evenly mixed.
I'm going to make paper from this state.
Can you see it from here?
Can you see how it's being made into paper?
Wow, that's great.
See how it's spinning here?
It's spinning in a circular motion.
It's spinning like a drum.
The surface is a net.
It's spinning in a circular motion.
And it lifts up all the fibers with this water.
And because it's a net, only the fibers remain on top.
The water falls to the bottom.
I see.
Only the fibers move over here.
That's how paper is made.
So it's the water that's flowing, and everything else is going up?
That's amazing.
The drum keeps spinning in circles.
The paper is being made continuously.
That's great. Oh, my God.
Um, have you two seen this?
The part where they make washi like this. Oh, yes!
That, too, is made by shaking the fibers on a net like this
and stretching it evenly, they make it, right?
Only the water falls down, so only the fibers are on top.
But that one has to be taken piece by piece.
This one goes around in a circle and makes it continuously.
Amazing!
They make it in thousands of meters, tens of thousands of meters.
Wow! That's fast!
That's amazing!
So it's the same as the store? Like that one?
Yes, the picture is the same.
Like a conveyor belt.
Yes, it is, yes, it is.
But it's still wet.
Indeed.
So it's not quite paper yet.
That's why we're going to dry it after this.
Yes, sir.
The paper was just sent like this, right?
And the drum above is drying the paper.
It's a drum.
Yes, sir.
It's spinning in a circle, too.
The surface of the drum is thick.
So it's stuck to it and the water is blown away.
And the water is blown away.
That's right.Oh, yeah, that's right.
Simply put, you squeeze the iron when it's wet.
It's like you're making the water fly away.
It would be easier to understand if you imagine it like that.
Yes, it is.
And then, the thing attached to the surface in such a way finally dries up.
And then it turns into paper and comes out from this side.
Oh, is this it?
Oh, wow! Wow! It's so peppy!
It's paper!
That's great!
When it's in that state, it's already dry.
Even if there is nothing underneath, it will flow continuously.
Is it completely dry?
It's completely dry.
Wow!
Oh, it's coming out infinitely.
Hey! That's great!
Yeah, as long as you have the raw material, it'll keep coming out indefinitely.
Wow!
It's like a big roll of toilet paper.
Well, but I think the image is similar.
I see.
I'll take you to the last step.
Here you go.
Thank you. Hello.
Oh!
Oh, my God, that's my hair.
That's the hair that just came out.
It's finally going to curl up like this.And it finally winds up like this.
It's an amazing
It's a process.
It's very colorful, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Usually, people think of shoji paper as pure white.
We have this kind of
Shoji paper with patterns on it
We can also make
It's so cute!
It's not a print anymore.
There's no printing process.
Then how do they do it?
That's for sure.
It's a mystery, isn't it?
You mix them together?
The actual colored washi paper
Cut into small pieces.
And that's the raw material I mentioned earlier.
That's right.
It is mixed when making paper.
To make paper.
It's amazing.
You never know what kind of patterns you'll get.
It's random.
Wow.
You don't lose them?
It's supposed to be there, but it's not.
It's like it's concentrated or something, but it's not here.I'm concentrating or not here.
is...
Oh, my gosh.
I'm making all kinds of adjustments so that it doesn't happen.
That's great.
So, approximately how many pieces per square meter?
per square meter
per square meter.
If it's less than that, it's no good.
Not too many
That's what we do.
I'm making a paper like this
I've been making paper like this.
That's great.
I was able to get the pattern
so that the pattern is evenly distributed.
Hee~~
We make about 3,000 to 4,000 meters of this kind of paper.
3000m?
We roll up about 3000m in one roll and store the paper.
For example, shoji paper at a home improvement store, 3m or 7m thin paper.
That's the kind of product.
This roll is later processed into that kind of product.
Wow, it's getting bigger and bigger.
How long will it take to make one roll? About 800 meters of this paper is being rolled up now.
About 800 meters of this paper will be rolled up.
So it will be rewound in about 4000 meters.
This paper will be rewound about 4 times longer than this one.I'm going to roll it up, so this paper will be about four times larger than this.
Four times? Wow.
Even more.
Is this big enough?
Please subscribe to our channel.
Thank you very much for letting us observe the construction today.
Thank you very much.
We at the Muramata Festival
I heard that the Murakata Festival is also putting a lot of effort into echo activities.
I would like to make paper from plastic bottles
I would like to make paper from plastic bottles and make Japan.
Can you help us with that too?
Yes, I would.
I think we can cooperate with you in making paper.
We collect plastic bottles.
We collect plastic bottles and make them into fiber.
If we ask you to do that, is that possible?
Yes, we can.
We would be very grateful for your cooperation.
Thank you very much.
I would like to see the paper mixed with polyester in more detail.
May I?
Yes, please.
Then I'll show you to this side.
Thank you very much.
This is the paper I was telling you about earlier.
This is the paper we make by mixing polyester fiber.
You can actually touch it.
Wow.
Amazing.Amazing.
Smooth and coarse.
Yeah, it is.
There's some kind of incredible reflection... of light.
Yeah, there's light.
That's amazing.
It's so smooth.
Amazing.
It doesn't feel like polyester at all.
I can't tell.
It's got some kind of writing on it.
Are you sure?
Thank you very much.
What color should it be?
Blue, blue, blue.
Thank you very much.
What are you going to write?
I'm gonna write my name.
Okay, okay, okay.
That's great.
I don't think I've ever written anything before.
You're right.
Isn't it easy to write?
Better than I thought it would be.
That's great.
Is there anything you want to talk about, Hossa?
What?
I don't know.My own image is...
PET Bottle-kun is a fiber and mixes it.
Plastic Bottle Boy...
Hmmm...
I want to make a character.
Write it down.
What?
Just Mr. Plastic Bottle.
I'll make my own Mr. Plastic Bottle.
Okay, okay.
It's beautiful.
Thank you for watching.
I put a hat on it, but it looks a little bit like shampoo.
LOL!
I put the hat on and it looks like shampoo.
It does look like shampoo.
Shampoo bottle
It looks like a shampoo damele.
Well, it's sad. I put a hat on a PET bottle.
This is the little one, Mr. PET Bottle.
The big one.
Not 500.
Yes, the little one.
Miyu, isn't it a little peculiar?
Isn't the cap long?
You know, the jagged part.
But maybe a little shorter.
So it's half open?
Jagged.
That's right. Yes, you did.
I can see it.
Half-open
Half-open plastic bottle.
Well, that's nice, isn't it?
So many personalities!
This is Mr. Plastic Bottle, and this is Little Plastic Bottle.
Oh, it's a little bit...
It's got eyelashes and a ribbon.
Eyelashes.
You see the eyelashes?
I thought your eyes were battened down.
Oh, no, I can't see them.
I thought you couldn't see.
Oh, my eyelashes.
Eyelashes. Don't tell anyone.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's like, "Stop.
Oh, stop.
Stop.
Why are you stopping?
And the eyes...
Stop.
I see.
Thank you for turning 6,000 times.
One thousand.
I'm going to give you a plastic bottle.
If they fall out, it's bad for the environment.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.Mm-hmm.
So, that sad plastic bottle that fell down...
and Miyu-chan and Riroa-chan meet and
and have them save him.
Oh, sure.
I'm sure that's true.
Yes, yes, yes
The world.
"Idemyu is going to save the world.
A picture book about saving the world.
That's good.
It's good.
Save the world from what?
That's why it's sad.
Sad, fallen, abandoned.
It's sad. It's hot.
Just save it.
Sad, plastic bottle, make you happy
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I heard it's at least 12 pages.
Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
Yes. Yes.Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
Good.
Check.
Kombu.
Kyu.
Yes.That's it.
You tell him I'll give it to you. You suck on it and give it to him.
Clean it up, peel off the label, and give it a little pichon.
And then you just go back to the factory and hope that it will reopen.
And the factory goes round and round and round and round and round and round and round and round and round and round and round and round and round and round and round.
And then it's dried and turned into a 4000 meter bottle.
PET bottles! And then we'll be done.
Next time I'm working with some students...
I'm thinking of a story like this. What do you think?
I'll try to put together a light four-panel comic for them.
A four-panel comic? That's difficult.
It doesn't have to be a four-panel comic at all.
I'll think about it.
I'll think of something.
Here you go.
This is Patti.
It's done!
All right! It's done!
Oh!
Yay!
Let's show them!
Ready!
Dooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo!
First of all, there's a plastic bottle that's full of bread.
I turned it into orange juice.
Orange juice!
It was full of orange juice.
Then someone took the cap off And then somebody took this cap off.
and drank it, and it was half full.
And he drank it.
But at this time, my friends are fine because they're here.
But one day, they are floating in the sea and crying.
Mr. Plastic Bottle, I'm so sad!
He's crying.
Then Lil' Mew found him...
He found Mr. Plastic Bottle.
Biccone.
And this Lil' Mew is here!
He washed him clean, and the plastic bottle became shiny.
And here, too, is omitted.
And then he became hair... again!
And this Lil' Mew is omitted here, too.
Happy ending!
It's a happy ending!
So cute!
I like it.
It's hard.
I knew it would be weird, but it was hard.
I'll be back with the plastic bottles.
Yay! Thank you so much!
That's great.
What about you, Mew?
I'm going to make a presentation too.
I wrote it in four panels.
Four panels.
First of all, a plastic bottle filled with green tea.
Yes, yes. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, it's like someone buys it for you and you're happy.
It's like the start of a new job.
It's true, it's true, it's true.
It's starting to do its job.
And then the plastic bottle is thrown into the ocean...
And I'm sad, sad, sad.
Third.
But then, Lil' Mew appears and realizes that the plastic bottle is Lil' Mew.
After omitting a lot of things, Ril Mew and the PET bottle full of green tea hold hands and get along well with each other again.
Oh, I see... back to the PET bottle, Mew Mew.
Mew Mew is back in the plastic bottle again, and he's a friend...
I see.
It's a happy ending.
Mr. Pet Bottle is me, Lil' Me.
I'm the same height as Lil' me.
That's right.
That's pretty big.
The same height as Lil.
It's all about the end, isn't it?
Are we going to return to Mr. Plastic Bottle?
Back to Mr. Plastic Bottle?
Yes, it's a picture book.
I thought it would make you think, "Oh, it's Mr. Plastic Bottle," when you look at it.
I'll change it to paper, too.
In various ways.
I thought tomorrow's picture book will be about Mr. Plastic Bottle.
You can't move by yourself.
That's why.So.
I've only got my hands, though.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It doesn't feel good to hold hands.
Yeah, it does.
It's nice.
It's spread out.
I think I can make it.
Wow, that's great!
It's Yotchan Ueno!
No, it's wonderful!
Maybe we can make it together.
I can't believe you could make that much in 10 or 20 minutes.
Yes, it is!
It's amazing!
Thank you very much.
Now that we're here, I'd like to go back to the students.
If it's possible, I'd like to work with students again.
If it's possible, I'd be happy to work with students to write down the entire contents based on this.
Maybe we can make it together.
I'd like to make it!
I really want to make it.
It would be like a picture book of God.
If it's okay with both of you, I'm totally fine with this kind of story.
I'm so happy.
It's good.
It's okay?
It's not up to me.
L'il Mu is good? You want L'il Mu?
Let's do it.
I'm so happy!
It's a picture book about L'il Mu.
It's a picture book about Lil Mu.
I was thinking that if it's a picture book, it should have a cover.
For example, we're planning to write the cover of the book outdoors on the day of the festival.
I see.
A coloring book would be a good idea.
That's for sure.
Maybe even small children could color in the book, and it would become the cover, and the inside would be written by everyone's own work.
That's great!
We could really do that.
I like the idea of everyone making the cover together.
It would be nice.
Something I made.
Oh, wow.
That's great.
Let's do it.
Let's do it!
I didn't think it would look this good.
I'm so happy!
And this project, too.
Yes, that's what I mean. I learned a lot from the tour of the factory today, didn't I?
I learned a lot.
I discovered many things.
Well, you know, there were many images of picture book production today, too,
I was thinking about how to make the cover, who would draw the inside, and so on. I'm also thinking about what to do for the cover, and the contents, and who will draw them.
Well, but what should we do?
I thought it would be good to make the cover together, like a coloring book.
I thought it would be nice if we could all work on it together,
If they really adopt this story,
If they really adopt this story, don't you want to draw it by yourselves?
I still want to draw it by myself, but..,
I don't know, but I think there are other topics that only Lil and Miyu can come up with, so I don't know.
I've learned a lot from students, too.
It would be great if we could work together.
I think we can make something good.
I think we can do it.
I'm looking forward to it.
Yes, that's what I've been thinking,
Goo Goo Channel will be
From November 3rd to 5th,
Minakata Festival will be held from November 3 to 5,
We will be working on the Minakata Festival,
R Fujimoto and Batention will play a central role,
We will be uploading the videos on YouTube.
I am looking forward to your comments. We would be very happy if you could comment on the video and let us know what you think.
Please do.
Bye bye,
Bye bye!